

# SAMIM OSMAN (Backend Developer with Python Django)

To establish as a Python Django Web Developer in local organizations by offering the value/benefit Programming, Development, Problem Solving. Want to establish myself as a Sr. Developer within 4-5 years.





ADDRESS: H-04/1904, AGB Colony, Motijheel, Dhaka-1000

#### TECHNICAL SKILL

- Programming Skills
- Web Development
- Problem Solving
- Web Design (Basic)
- Digital Marketing
- Basic Graphics Design

### SOFT SKILL

- Good Communication
- Team-Building
- Time Managements
- Organizing

#### **A** LANGUAGES

English –Writing, Speaking & Listing

Bangla –

Writing, Speaking & Listing

#### 4 HOBBIES

- Coding
- Story Reading
- Traveling

#### **EXPERIENCE**

#### **Industrial Training | Aug 2023 to Nov 2023**

Creative It Institute – Web Development with Python Django

• From August 2023 - November 2023 we did our industrial attachment training for Diploma-in-Engineering, the subject of our training was web development with python Django. There we completed a few projects including a simple e-commerce website.

#### Online Business Marketing/Sales | Jan 2020 to Aug 2023

Safa World (Owner) - Online Shopping Facebook Page

- I started my own online shopping business in January 2020, I generate sales through marketing through Facebook, Instagram, YouTube and various social media.
- I work in graphic design, creating various content for my online shop business.
- And I do the work of WordPress website maintenance, sales generating, social media paid marketing.
- I have 3 year experience in online product marketing and sales. For the last 3 year I have been marketing and selling products as a merchant on Facebook, Instagram, Websites and several e-commerce websites.

# Data Analysis for "Updating the Revised Strategic Transport Plan for Dhaka | 4 Month Project

SIGMIND.ai, Software Technology Park, Janata Tower, Kawran Bazar

• This is a 4 month project. I worked for SIGMIND.ai on this 4 month project. The task of this project is to analyze the data. All vehicle images collected from CCTV footage are selected by category.

#### Computer Operator | Sep 2021 to July 2022

Safe Education Family, Rajarbagh, Dhaka

• Safe Education Family is a private coaching center and Kindergarten School. And I worked there honestly for about 9 months as computer operator, compose, typist.



#### **EDUCATION**

**Diploma-in-Engineering: Computer Technology | 2019-20** 

From, National Polytechnic Institute - Passed in 2023

**Secondary School Certificate: Science | 2017-18** 

From, Motijheel Colony High School with a GPA 4.28 out of 5.00



# SAMIM OSMAN (Backend Developer with Python Django)

#### BIOGRAPHY

- Name: Samim Osman (Sabuj)
- Father's Name: *Md. Montaz Uddin*
- Mother's Name: Selina Begum
- Nationality:Bangladeshi
- Religion:
- Gender: *Male*
- Marital Status: Single

#### 🚣 My Profiles

- Facebook: facebook.com/samim.o. sabuj03/
- Github: github.com/samimosm ansabuj/
- Portfolio:
  samimosmansabuj.gith
  ub.io/samimosman.gith
  ub.io/
- WhatsApp: 01775155760
- My Youtube: youtube.com/channel/U CkYCdM2TcnOOPZQ V7J4PTqQ
- My Work And Portfolio: pyteam-c.com

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

Python Django (Certificate): Creative IT Institute

Course: Web Development with Python Django

Digital Marketing (Certificate): LEDP (Government)

Batch No: 862, Registration No: 336777

Web Design (Basic): *Dreamland IT*Course: **HTML5, CSS and MySQL.** 



#### **SKILLS**

#### **Basic Skills-**

Rest API, Php, HTML & CSS, Bootstrap, WordPress Customization, Graphics Design, Digital Marketing.

#### **Advanced Skills -**

Python, Web Development with Python Django, Python OOP, Problem Solving, Teaching, Digital Marketing, Microsoft Office, Fast Typist, Data Entry, Customer Management, Good Communications

# LANGUAGE PROFICIENCY

#### **ENGLISH-**

Reading- Intermediate - Writing- Intermediate Listening- Beginner - Speaking: Beginner

#### **BANGLA-**

Reading- Native - Writing- Native Listening- Native - Speaking: Native



#### REFERENCE

#### MD. ASHRAFUL ISLAM-

Sr. Teacher, Head of Computer Department National Polytechnic Institute, Firmgate, Dhaka

#### MD SYDUL AMIN-

Jr. Python Faculty Members. Creative IT Institute, Dhanmondi, Dhaka